Michael Cai

Software Engineer

Michael Cai is a software engineer with three years of professional experience, two years of academic research experience, and a Master's degree in computer science. He has worked in microservice development and has a passion for building out CI/CD processes and internal tooling.

EXPERIENCE

AVEVA (Formerly OSIsoft) — Software Developer II

March 2022 - PRESENT

- Worked on core infrastructure microservices and libraries for AVEVA Data Hub (Formerly known as OSIsoft Cloud Services).
- Developed components for an internal tool to migrate customers between live production environments of two products.
- Worked on creating developer microservice templates to transition teams from Service Fabric to Kubernetes development.
- A key contributor to the team's shared CI/CD and operations based work. Regularly creating and maintaining pipelines for automated security scanning, build processes, and deployments.
- Created shareable IaC Bicep modules for setting up SQL Servers with standardized authentication using Managed Identities.

Arizona State University — *Graduate Services Assistant*

January 2021 - December 2021

- Lead TA for two courses, Algorithms in Computational Biology and Introduction to Theoretical Computer Science.
- Designed a project for an introductory machine learning module.

OSIsoft — Software Developer Intern

Summer 2019 & Summer 2020 & Summer 2021

EDUCATION

Arizona State University — MS in Computer Science

January 2021 - December 2021

 Thesis - An Application of Attention for the Prediction of TCR-Epitope Binding Affinity

Arizona State University — BS in Computer Science

August 2017 - December 2020

• Graduated from Barrett, The Honors College

Scottsdale, Arizona linkedin.com/in/michael-r-cai

SKILLS

C#

Python

Bicep

Kubernetes

Helm Templating

CI/CD YAML Pipelines

Azure

.NET Development

Entity Framework for SQL Server and CosmosDB

Unit Testing

Git

TOOLS AND PROCESSES

Agile Development

Visual Studio

Azure DevOps

AWARDS

Moeur Award Awarded to undergraduate students who completed their degree with a 4.0 GPA in under 8 semesters.

PUBLICATIONS

"ATM-TCR: TCR-epitope binding affinity prediction using a multi-head self-attention model" - Cai M, Bang S, Zhang P, Lee H. Frontiers in Immunology. July 6th, 2022.